Md Faisal Hossain

Cumilla, Bangladesh



hello.faisalhossain@outlook.com

+ +088 01701-269570



in linkedin.com/in/mdfaisalhossain1

https://web-faisal.github.io/profile/

Profile

Hi! I'm software engineer. My Experienced Data Entry Operator with a demonstrated history of working in the government administration industry. I am a business development partner of Netizen IT Limited. Skilled in Python (Programming Language), JavaScript (Programming Language), Software Management, Data Entry, HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language), CSS (Cascading Style Sheets), SCSS (Senior Citizens Savings Scheme), Bootstrap (framework), React (framework), Node JS, MongoDB, git, bash, GitHub, Digital Marketing, Database Management System (DBMS), E-mail Design, Unity (game engine), Filmora X, Canva.

Experience



Programmer

Netizen IT Limited

Jan 2022 - Present (1 month +)

- Compiled [Timeframe] budget reports, financial spreadsheets and organizational charts to support business operations and improve office organization.
- Maintained databases, mailing lists, telephone networks, and other information to facilitate functioning of health education programs.

Data Entry Operator

Income Tax Department of UK Jan 2021 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

Game Developer

Unity Technologies

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

- Coding is the best way to have fun.
- · You can create any type of program with coding.
- You can create any kind of game with unity
- Develop original content through social listening and independent sources.

COMPUTER SKILL'S

Programming: Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript (Programming Language)

• HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) • CSS (Cascading Style Sheets)

• SCSS (Senior Citizens Savings Scheme) • Git • Bash • Github

Framework & Library: React is • Node is • Bootstrap • MongoDB

Game Engine: Unity (Game Engine)

Software Platforms: Data Entry • Figma (Software) • Wondershare Filmora • Canva

Microsoft Office

Applications: PyCharm • Visual Studio Code • Sublime Text

Platforms: Windows OS

OTHER SKILL'S

• Database Management System (DBMS) • E-mail Design

• Software management • Project Management

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Computer Science: Code.org & MIT

Crash course on Python: Google & FreeCodeCamp.org

Crash course on JavaScript: Data Camp

Font-End web developer: Programming Hero

Licenses & certifications

Viving Certificate of Accomplishment - typing.com

Issued Feb 2022

Credential ID: 187899231-130518021

INTERESTS

- Programming
- Machine learning technology
- Robotics
- Computer Science

Signature by *Faisal*